A Guide to the Society of the Descendants of Peter Francisco papers, 1971-2013
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Society of the Descendants of Peter Francisco papers, 1971-2013
The Library of Virginia
50844, 50845
2.25 cu. ft and 5 boxes
Society of the Descendants of Peter Francisco
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of the Society of the Descendants of Peter Francisco, Anne Wilson, treasurer; and Donald R. Pruitt
Historical Information
The Society of the Descendants of Peter Francisco was founded in 1971 to promote knowledge of Peter Francisco (1760-1831), a Revolutionary War hero; to provide information on the Peter Francisco family genealogy; and to repair and restore Locust Grove, the home of Peter Francisco. The society also promotes the history of the American Revolution and the heritage of the Portuguese-American community.
Scope and Content
Papers, 1971-2013, of the Society of the Descendants of Peter Francisco (SDPF), relating to the general operations of the SDPF, its efforts to promote knowledge of Peter Francisco (1760-1831), its membership, its finances, and its relations with other historical and cultural organizations. Papers include applications, articles, audiocassettes, biographies, books, brochures, bylaws, cards, certificates, clippings, correspondence, emails, forms, genealogies, insurance policies, invitations, invoices, lists, maps, minutes, newsletters, notes, obituaries, photographs, poems, programs, receipts, reports, schedules, speeches, tax records, and other papers.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into the following series:
Series I: Bylaws.
Series II: Newsletters, 1971-1985, 2000-2013.
Series III: Meetings, 1989-2013.
Series IV: Membership, 1971-2013.
Series V: Membership files, 1997-2008.
Series VI: Correspondence, 1971-2012.
Series VII: Financial Records, 1971-2012.
Series VIII: Peter Francisco.
Series IX: Locust Grove, 1973-1996.
Series X: Genealogy.
Series XI: Portuguese-American societies, 1995-2010.
Series XII: General Papers.
Series XIII: Clippings, 1935-2007.
Series XIV: Publications.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Related Material
Edith Francisco Buckley papers, 1908-2013 (LVA accession 50846).
Contents List
- Series I: Bylaws., Extent: 1 box. (Box 1)
  Bylaws contain the bylaws of the SDPF detailing its structure and operation and including revisions and motions.
  - Bylaws, including revisions, 2001, 2010, undated. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Suggestions, motions. (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Series II: Newsletters, 1971-1985, 2000-2013., Extent: 1 box. (Box 1)
  Newsletters, 1971-1985, 2000-2013, consisting of newsletters of the SDPF containing news of the SDPF, its meetings and activities, and its individual members. The 2000-2013 newsletters are titled The Virginia Giant.
  - Newsletters, 1971-1980. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Newsletters, 1981-1985. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Newsletters, 2000-2001. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Newsletters, 2002-2003. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Newsletters, 2004-2005. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Newsletters, 2006-2007. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Newsletters, 2008-2009. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Newsletters, 2010-2011. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Newsletters, 2012-2013. (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Series III: Meetings, 1989-2013., Extent: 1 box. (Box 1)
  Meetings, 1989-2013, containing cassette tapes, clippings, correspondence, minutes, photographs, programs, schedules, and other papers from the SDPF's wreath-laying ceremonies and Spring meetings, the SDPF's Fall meetings, and the SDPF's 2008 Spring meeting held at the Guilford Court House National Battlefield.
  - Spring and Fall meeting schedule, 2000-2013. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Wreath-laying ceremony, 2000-2001. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Wreath-laying ceremony, 2002. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Wreath-laying ceremony, 2003-2007. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Fall meeting, 1989-1991, 1999-2005. (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Fall meeting, 2006-2012. (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Guilford Court House Battlefield meeting, 2008 March 14-16. (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Series IV: Membership, 1971-2013., Extent: 1 box. (Box 2)
  Membership, 1971-2013, containing applications, correspondence, lists, receipts, and other papers regarding membership in the SDPF.
  - Membership lists, 1988, 1999-2013. (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Membership forms, A-W. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1971-1987. (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1993-1996. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1997-1999, 2002, undated. (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous papers, 1992, 2002, 2011, undated. (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Series V: Membership files, 1997-2008., Extent: 1 box. (Box 2)
  Membership files, 1997-2008, contains applications, cards, clippings, correspondence, emails, genealogies, lists, notes, photographs, and poems regarding first-time and renewing memberships, meetings, SDPF activities, and the SDPF's relations with other organizations. Series is arranged alphabetically.
  - Membership files, 1997-2008, A-B. (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Membership files, 1997-2008, C-D. (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Membership files, 1997-2008, E-F. (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Membership files, 1997-2008, G-J. (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Membership files, 1997-2008, K-N. (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Membership files, 1997-2008,O-Z. (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Series VI: Correspondence, 1971-2012., Extent: 1 box. (Box 3)
  Correspondence, 1971-2012, contains biographies, brochures, clippings, correspondence, emails, forms, invitations, invoices, photographs, poems, and other papers concerning the life of Peter Francisco, Francisco family genealogy, activities of the SDPF, and news from individual members.
  - Correspondence, 1971-1987. (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1993-1997, 2000. (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 2002-2004. (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 2005-2007. (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 2008-2009. (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 2010-2012. (Box 3, Folder 6)